I get paid $50,000 a day to speak. Damn.
And in this video, I'm going to share my
public speaking secrets with you by
breaking down a recent talk that I gave
in Thailand for the legendary talk more.
As the world becomes more AI, the need
for and value of public speaking will
increase. If you can look an audience in
the eye, speak in command language that
will travel through the ears to the
brain and then into the heart that
completely changes somebody's
perspective. If you can transform them
from limited to empowered, from I can't
to I must, from uncertainty to
absolutely to help them find more of who
they are and have more of that show up
in the world, then riches, my friend,
can flow into your bank account as well
as into your soul. I teach to you today
not with theory, but actual clips of me
speaking in front of a real audience
with real stakes and real money on the
line. I'm going to play you the clip,
then we're going to undress the science
and the art underneath of it. You ready
to go? Well, let's start at the start.
Okay. So, watch what I do immediately
when I take the stage. Thank you. Thank
you. Thank you. All right. I don't have
a lot of time, so we're going to cook
right away. Uh Taki told me, he said,
"Do a 15-minute introduction of who you
are, what you stand for, all your none
of that [__] right? [laughter]
I'm going to show you 15 steps for
webinar success. This will be useful to
you if you never run a webinar in your
entire life because you're going to
learn more important than a webinar,
which is how to make an offer. You're
going to learn communication strategies.
You're going to learn how to actually
control a market with the frame and
presence that you show up with that
market. Then I'm going to do some sneaky
[__] Put it inside your unconscious.
And when you are least aware, the lesson
will come at a time that's most
opportune to you.
>> Okay. So, there's three things I did
immediately. The first one is I made a
joke. Breaking the tension with a joke
is a great way to start a conversation.
Now, in this case, Taki told me
specifically, don't get up there and
don't go on and on and on. And so many
speakers, they spend too much time
proving how amazing they are. They
should show how amazing they are with
their presentation. So, that's the first
thing that I did. The second thing is I
set the frame immediately. I explained
that even if you don't do webinars, this
will be useful for you because I knew
most of that audience hadn't done a
webinar yet. And then the third thing
was is I use conversational hypnosis.
And this is something I don't see very
many people use in their public
presentations is I use the vague wording
of you will discover things and they may
show up in ways that you are unsure of
exactly consciously yet until you see
them in place and then once you do you
will look back and be like wow that was
super effective. So, by using both
conscious and unconscious communication
strategies in public speaking, you will
hit an audience at two levels and you
are significantly more likely to convert
an audience because they will be, "Wait
a second, how will I know when I use
this?" Oh, Jason says it will just show
up and they will accept that. If they
don't accept it, it doesn't cost us
anything. But if they do accept it, we
get a happier audience because they get
a better result.
>> How many parts? Awesome. Good crowd,
right? First part is the core offer. is
what they will pay for after they see
how cool the free thing is in the
webinar or the thing that you trained in
the webinar. So the reality is the
webinar is entirely a setup for the
offer that you make at the end of the
webinar. Now is that manipulative?
>> Okay, so immediately what you want to do
is establish a call and response with
your audience. Have it be a conversation
more so than a presentation. This gets
compliance. This demonstrates authority.
You tell them what to do and then they
do it. So I say the the offer has five
parts. How many parts? And then they say
five. If you get the cadence of always
call response, you tell them what to do
and they do it. This audience will go
anywhere with you. And then the next
thing I do here is a combination of
humor again. And you should track in
your presentations how many laughs per
minute do I achieve? And you want it to
be probably about one laugh per minute
on average if not more. And one of the
ways I use humor here that's so tough
for many people as public speakers is
the pause. Is this manipulation?
And then I get really quiet and the
audience gets somewhat uncomfortable.
And when people get uncomfortable, they
laugh to break the tension of being
uncomfortable and then they accept it.
Okay. Yes, it is manipulation, but
manipulation might be good. So, this is
a subtle way to undermine an audience's
resistance to a concept, but also at the
same time, it establishes a deeper frame
of authority because I'm challenging the
notion that [snorts] most other
presenters won't challenge them on. Too
many people who do public speaking, they
cater and I hate this so much. If you
can challenge an audience to go to a
deeper level, you will get more
authority and more respect from that
audience.
>> I would like to buy but do [laughter]
and I say, "What about this reason?"
"Okay, what about this reason? Maybe
what about this reason?" "Okay, sure.
Shut take my money. Now, this is how we
get them to do that. Typically, the
thing that you sell the hardest is the
thing you give away for free. Write that
down. I'm going to say that again. The
thing that you push the most, the thing
that you sell the hardest is the thing
that you give away for.
>> Okay, so this is another master class in
rhetorical speech devices for public
speaking. I use a bumper sticker or what
we call a sound bite. And you should
have a running list of 25 of these. When
you hit a stage, you should have
rehearsed 25 like tweet tweetable lines
that you can rattle off at will whenever
you wish to that you can say as easily
as you know the name of your children.
And so in this case is the thing we sell
the hardest is the thing we give away
for free. Then I say write that down.
This is a command. Again we want to
create as much compliance for the
audience as possible to whatever we say.
And also on top of that I repeat it back
and then I let them fill in the blank.
So this is interaction in motion as we
shown earlier that call response effect
with the audience. Also on top of that
repetition
when you read stuff in print it's easy
to go back if you miss something. When
you hear it spoken in real time one word
after the next. It will go in one ear
and out the other. And so you should
learn to speak in repetition, which is
what I've done here. I made the bumper
sticker moment. I had them write it
down. I repeated it again with a pause
so they can fill in the blank. And now
it's really stuck
>> value. And this is a big secret, right?
And then the risk. Everything has risk.
You want to know the biggest secret to
the hundreds of millions of dollars I
produce myself and clients. Would you
like to know what it is? Yes. We don't
sell the plan to heaven. We sell the
path out of hell.
>> So this is another soundbite moment. And
also the setup. This is what you really
have to get good at when you're speaking
in front of a stage. You don't just
jackhammer the information. You don't
just say to them, "Here's what you do,
then you do this, then you do that, then
you do this, then you do that." I say,
"Would you like to know the biggest
secret that ever exists? Would you
really want to know the secret of all
secrets when it comes to X, Y, and Z?"
And this creates excitement. And this is
lean-in kind of language. And people are
like, "Yes, I want to hear it." Because
again, people's retention when they're
hearing things spoken out loud is very
low. And so we want to have less
information, but we want to have the
information that we communicate land as
powerfully as possible. And because we
have a live audience, we can get
compliance again. They can say, "Yes,
Jason, I want to know. Yes, tell me.
Yes, I'm interested. Yes, I'm excited."
And we're commanding the language
vocally. Notice how I change the
tonality to set up the point, get them
leaning in, and then I deliver the point
of the product, right? That's good.
Okay. And scarcity. People will not
change a routine even if that routine
harms them. Would you agree with that?
>> Yeah. They say, "I know I shouldn't eat
this," and then they eat it. "I know I
shouldn't drink this," and then they
drink it, right? "I know I should be
doing this instead of that." But they do
this instead of that.
>> This is another great example of
repetition. It's done slightly
differently. So, if you're always
repetitive in the same way, the audience
becomes bored out of their mind with
you. But if you understand the principle
of repetition and find the variation of
different ways that you can repeat a
message, the more effective it is. And
this is yet another bumper sticker
moment or another sound bite as we call
it. By the way, notice how I am creating
cadence in how I'm delivering the
information so the audience can follow
along, follow along, follow along, and
then I stop and then they're like, "Oh
my god, back to consciousness. I got to
figure out and I got to stay on my toes.
I got to keep up with this guy." So, I
can follow along simultaneously most of
the time, but I know every so often he
throws the right hook. So, I always got
to be focused with my brain on
everything that he's saying and he's
doing when he's presenting. So even when
you do all of this right, the result is
a majority of the people that should buy
for you will not buy for you. And that's
okay because we only need a couple at a
time to say yes. And so this is who we
sell to. This is who we serve. This is
who we help. But you have to get it out
of your head. Conversion rate and you
need to get into your heart. Souls. How
many souls am I going to touch? How many
souls am I going to move? And so we use
both the carrot and the stick. We use
both all the value and plus all of the
risk mitigated. And we do pretty well
despite the fact that most people are
going to be programmed to say no to you
even though the best thing for them to
do is to say yes to you. Is this
resonating?
>> Contrasting forces, paired opposites.
People who should say yes to you say no
to you. We don't just give carrot. We
also give stick. It's not just about
reward. It's all about risk. So when you
put two things against each other, it
makes it easier for people to understand
your point. It also allows you to speak
more rhythmatically and so people can
follow along easier and they can have
that cadence and that rhythm that they
can keep up with. And then again, we
throw that right hook at them at the
last second. I don't mess around. I
expect that I will have to work hard to
get somebody to say yes, who should say
yes. And so this is why we do everything
we can to make the offer as irresistible
as humanly possible. And then we write
the webinar afterwards or the VSSL or
the offer dock.
>> Really powerful thing here. So notice
the repetition or the VSSL or the offer
dock or the thing you'll get distracted
by next month. So I have to broaden it
back because the audience is how does
this relate to me if I don't do
webinars? How does this topic apply to
me specifically and I know the room and
you have to know the room. And that last
point that I drove home both shows I
know the room and creates the deepest
authority. So I'm not just another
speaker with average authority. I am the
speaker with the most authority. I say,
"Or whatever AI will distract you by
next month." And then they laugh cuz
they're like, "Man, Flatlin called me on
my [__] Even though he is liking in
terms of developing rapport with me to
get me to like him, he's not afraid to
challenge me. He's not afraid to call me
out. And he knows my limitations. And he
understand me. He's done his homework to
have the privilege to speak to me on a
stage."
>> Will this vary if we're doing a book
call? Yes or no?
>> Yes. Right. Will this vary? depending
upon what market we may be in a war
price point that we saw. Yes or no? Yes.
Right. This is a map, but the map is not
the territory. The details may change,
but the structure is important because
we spent a few minutes on here's what I
got for you, a few minutes on here's
what your investment is, a lot of time
on here's all the other stuff that I'm
going to give to you to help you and
then the most time on
>> risk. So, you're picking up the patterns
by now hopefully and it's really easy to
get good at these patterns. You just
drill them repeatedly. The other thing
that you do here is you anticipate where
the audience will make excuses. So I
bring it up very early on that will this
work in this scenario? Not exactly. Will
it work in that scenario? Not exactly.
Will you have to adjust it for this
other scenario over here which I know
all of these scenarios are relevant to
this audience. I say yes because what
people want is precise made to fit exact
for them which you can never give in a
room full of people with all kinds of
different backgrounds. So you make the
general point. You address how it needs
to be changed to the specific, but then
you allow them to know that it's okay
for them to take the general strategy
and slightly adjust it and tweak it as
needed to their particular circumstance.
So the whole webinar, by the way, this
is a little secret on the slides. Write
this down is everything that you sell
needs to be set up several times
throughout the webinar presentation. So
if I'm going to sell a community, I
should talk about in the introduction
how a challenge in this space is the
fact that too many of us are doing it
alone. Because later on, coincidentally,
when we offer community, we've already
given them a reason to want a community.
Does that make sense? And then we will
show as an example in the content
section the difference of somebody who
won in a community and somebody who lost
outside of a community. So then they
think gee I wish I had a community to be
a part of. I give you guys you guys
laugh but this is serious. Like most of
you are like your raw dog over here
doing whatever and at the end you hit
them upside the head with whatever the
liberals are. Yeah I didn't have a
chance to put this on the slides or
something along those lines. Here's a
really powerful secret that isn't on the
slides and then you explain it
extraneously. This is a showcase of your
expertise. you are okay with varying and
adjusting the programming from only
slides or only extemporaneous to a
mixture of both and you should do both.
So when I'm speaking I'm also reading an
audience and I'm seeing where should I
maybe go that I wasn't planning on going
based upon the real-time feedback I'm
getting from the crowd at large. And so
in this particular case an idea came to
me in the moment as I was talking to
this audience. I'm like, "This is
relevant to them." And I said, "This
isn't on any slides." And then not only
does that make it sound more attractive
and more valuable, but then I get to
show it without any props or without
anything to reference. And this shows
true mastery and expertise. And this
leaves the audience impressed upon and
said, "I better listen to this guy maybe
over every other speaker because he's
dropping some insights I haven't seen
anywhere else."
>> Little secret for you. This one is a
secret. This one is so good. Right. Done
for you is hard, laborious, difficult,
and client management expectation is
also frustrating. But if you do just
this much of the most important part of
the done for you, this is the 8020 rule,
right? If we find that step three is a
step that snags everybody up, step three
is easy for us to do for the client.
Step three gets a massive upside to the
client. We've done for you step three
only. And they still have to do step one
and two to qualify for step three. So we
increase the throughput of success of
our clients, which makes it easier to
sell. We decrease our cost to fulfill
both in time, effort, and energy and
money. And we get to now say DONE FOR
YOU IN OUR OFFER. If you put the words
done for you in an offer, usually
increases conversion. Now the done for
you, they don't pay for that. They get
it for free. Now they pay for this. They
get this for free. Is it really free? I
don't know. I'll leave it for the
scientists to figure out. Right? But the
human says free stuff. I like I want
free stuff. I will pay stuff to get free
stuff. Right? This is check logic,
right? She says,
>> so the point that I'm making here is
just reiterating the points that I've
made earlier before. Notice the
structure of speech. Notice the cadence.
Know the dueling forces, the contrasting
forces that we picked up in here. Notice
the setup that I build up the secret of
all secrets and the excitement in which
I'm delivering it. And then the
fill-in-the-blank line that I stop for
at the end so the audience can comply
with the request. Hopefully, you're
picking up on these little building
blocks that you should master
individually and then how you can
continually structure them and connect
them together. Winners, key success of
winning anything is consistency. You can
be a drug addict, you can be a
degenerate, you can be an [__] and
you can be very mediocre in your skill
level, but if you show up every [__]
day, this is why there's a lot of idiots
in America that make millions a year,
right? They're not very smart, but
they're very consistent. But you know
the commonality of a loser, they can be
nice, they can be good, and their mom
can hug and kiss them good night and
talk innocent by they can be sincere.
But if they're not consistent, they will
lose.
>> Are you picking up on the science that
I've been dropping so far? Because
again, this is mostly review more than
anything. Notice the language patterns,
notice the cadence, notice the
repetition, notice the slight variance
and rhythm to make it interesting
despite the fact that we're using the
same technique over and over again. But
what's really powerful about this is
wrapped around the technique is the
substance, the insight where I talk
about how you can be a loser and how you
can be a drug addict and how you can be
a degenerate and how you can be an idiot
and you can also be successful if you
have this one principle of consistency.
Yet, if you're nice and if you're kind
and if you're sincere, but you're
inconsistent, you will lose. And this is
what's called an aha moment. So, when
you have a really powerful insight, the
problem with most insights is if you
just give them out, like I could read a
book of quotes and I'll probably not
improve my life. You have to create a
context and condition that makes the
audience so receptive to hear it and so
impressed by the insight of it. that is
more important than the insight itself.
So this is me in action showing it and
when you speak it in real time in front
of an audience it has the biggest impact
possible.
>> Coaches have an unfair advantage when it
comes to this stuff because most of my
selling is in the coaching. Somebody
says to me, "Jason, I'm afraid I'm going
to fail." How would you know if you
fail? Uh they haven't thought that far
ahead, right? I said, "Well, could you
fail and still win?" Uh it's like, "What
if failing isn't failing, right? What if
you are so good at failing that you
succeed at failing? Could we call you a
failure if you're successful at
failing?" I go uh
and he said, "I'm not sure exactly when
you'll fail, but when you fail in this
certain way, you're going to succeed in
a way that even winners will fail at
succeeding at you'll succeed failing in
a way that you can't even remember how
you failed in the first place. And the
fact that you failed to wait here tells
me that you can fail with grace and
dignity. And I can't wait to encourage
you to fail, I'll be very upset if you
succeed too soon because people like you
only win in week three, not in week two,
not in week one." Right? [applause]
Yeah. Yeah. This is a spontaneous
clapping moment. And if you do not have
these in your presentation, you are not
communicating as effectively as
possible. Now, what I'm doing here is a
demonstration in front of them in real
time of the very thing that I'm teaching
them. So, it's no
doubt in their mind that this guy is
100% an expert and I should pay
attention and I should learn from him.
And by the way, I wasn't planning on
doing this, but when I started unpacking
a close technique that I was teaching
them and I picked up on the audience
resonating with it and liking it and
building up kind of this excitement
around them, I leaned into it more. A
lot of public speaking is dynamic. You
need to know the material cold. You need
to be an expert in the delivery of the
material. And then you have to be loose
enough to pick up on little signs to
make micro adjustments to get into the
heart of what that audience is
resonating with the most is what I did
here. But in your mind before you write
a presentation, optimize for those
spontaneous clapping moments. Go and
watch different speakers and how they
elicit them and then design them in your
own presentations. I like to prove
scarcity. Most people have fake
scarcity. [__] those people, right?
This is a pretty on- nose thing. Now,
you have to read your audience. So,
should you use cuss words? Maybe, maybe
not. That may be a personal decision for
you. I have no problem using cuss words.
I typically don't use them in front of
audiences unless I know that that is a
culturally accepted thing to do for
those audiences. And so in this
particular case, making the bold stance,
I say most people use fake scarcity.
[__] those people. It really cements
that authority. People care more who you
are than what you say. And they care who
you are based upon the authority that
you could communicate to that audience.
And some of this audience knew who I was
and some of this audience didn't know
who I was. So, I have to set the deep
authority frame as quickly as possible.
And this is one of the ways you can do
this is where you're so authentic and
present to your truth and show up and
communicate that to others. This is
where the deep resonation occurs cuz so
many people censor themselves too much
and they show up less of themselves in
front of others who are strangers who
have never seen them before and then
will never care to see them again
afterwards. Here's a little spoiler
alert for a lot of millions in my life.
After the first couple, I DON'T NOTICE
ANY difference in my lifestyle, right?
If anything, there's a negative
correlation between the money you make
past a diminishing return and the
happiness you have. That's going to [__]
a lot of you up. I'm sorry. Right. But
some of you have access to crisis as a
result of thinking about it over the
next couple of days. [laughter] I've
been there, right? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I
still flirt with it. Again, here's
another laugh. Now, this is a laugh on a
serious subject. I tell them, "Hey,
listen. I've made a whole bunch of money
and then I didn't get happier as a
result. In fact, I got worse off. And
you, some of you are going to have
trouble with this when you move into the
future and you struggle with it." And
they laugh even though it's a harsh
truth. Part of it is how I delivered it,
but part of it is they laugh because
they see that I understand them and they
laugh and they go, "God, this guy really
gets me. I'm uncomfortable with the
truth, but I can accept this truth." We
accept that truth through the laughter.
And then maybe I save them the problem.
I use this technique all over the place.
If you study me, you know this. I
exaggerate the negative so the person
can say, "Well, it's not that bad." or I
make the point of where it could go be
too scary for them. So when they dial it
back, they're less freaked out by maybe
I need to make an adjustment here. Maybe
I shouldn't overoptimize too much for
this thing. Because your goal here is to
help your audience be better than they
were before you spoke to them in the
first place. They leave that room a
different person than who they were when
they entered. And a lot of this is
talking to these deeper truths and
really breaking down things that are
hard for most people to hear, hard to
admit, and then finding out how to wrap
those around what you are saying when
you're teaching in your public
presentations. You are the exception.
You have came here mostly for pleasure.
That's weird to say that title, right?
Okay. [laughter]
Most of you are positively motivated to
grow your businesses. You are not your
market, right? Your market doesn't come
to you because they say life is good.
How do we make it better? Your customers
come to you because they say the house
is on fire. Do you have a fire hose?
This is why your customers come to you.
This is not pandering. You should never
pander in front of an audience. This is
the deeper truth spoken directly. I say
you are the exception. Now I use humor
again here. So when you're dropping that
real insight and you're wrapping it
around humor, it has a more powerful
effect. First of all, it's an emotional
state change cuz sitting and looking at
somebody on a stage is [__] boring
after about two seconds. So we create
entertainment. But again, a hard truth
or even a powerful truth wrapped around
humor will have so much more impact.
You'll also get better points on the
scorecard if they're scoring you as a
speaker. But in this particular case,
I'm acknowledging to the audience that
they are the exception to the rule that
they are here to cultivate and grow
themselves, but they cannot serve their
audience the same way. Instead, they
have to speak the language of the
audience. But again, notice the rhythm.
Notice how I set it up. Notice how I
created a call and response situation
from this audience and I stay in rapport
with this audience. Deep rapport to a
deeper truth spoken from a deeper
authority. This is what you solve for
when you write your presentations.
Jason, I'm afraid to do a webinar. Yeah,
I do. You know what happens when a
webinar fails? The people that attend
the webinar find your house. They kick
in your door. They drag you down the
street. They rip rip rip your clothes
off and they beat YOUR ASS IN PUBLIC.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU DON'T do a
webinar successfully. And they're like,
"Come on, Jason. It's not that bad."
Right? By the way, spoiler, you know
what happens to most people when they do
their first webinar ever?
>> Sucks.
>> Nobody gives a [__] RIGHT? YOU'RE NOT
GOOD ENOUGH FOR PEOPLE TO CARE ABOUT YOU
YET, RIGHT? You will silently do
mediocre work.
>> So, this is another somewhat spontaneous
clap, but a lot of spontaneous laughter.
Laughter, laughter, laughter, laughs per
minute. Now, I'm speaking on two levels
of communication here. This one's a
little bit of advanced. So, sometimes
when you tell a story of somebody else,
the lesson is not for the other
audience, but the audience you're
speaking. But if you tell them, "Here's
what you need to do," they come back
resistant. If you say here's something
this other audience needs to understand
and the lesson is equally applied to the
people that are listening to you, they
can become more receptive of it. So I'm
giving the example an exaggeration for
effect as we've seen earlier. If the
webinar sucks, they will come and they
will beat you up and then they that
makes them feel more likely to do a
webinar when they realize it's actually
not that bad. But then I tell them the
deep truth, right? Silent mediocrity.
That's how it will responded. And the
audience is like, "Okay, I need to get
out of my own way and I just need to do
the damn thing." And that's what I'm
really teaching them. I'm teaching them
by showing through a state of supreme
confidence that you're okay and that
yes, this is difficult, but you can do
this. And I know you can do this cuz
I've put in more work to understand how
to make people like you be able to do
this. And this is how it shows up on the
stage.
>> My favorite position, by the way, I
didn't have nice screenshots to just put
on slides and make it all tight and easy
for you. My favorite position is the
following. I'm going to show you how to
do it on your own for free and then I'm
going to make you an offer if you want
to do it with me. But before I make the
offer to you, I will first give you the
greatest lesson you've ever seen when it
comes to XYZ. Then we can have a
discussion on whether you do it by
yourself or if you pay me money and we
work together. Does that sound fair? I
get a 99% compliance rate, which is
really impressive because you know 3% of
the population is psychopathic, right?
Literally put 100 people on a webinar.
Three of them are [__] insane, right?
And I still get two of those three
agreeing with me on that. [laughter]
Yeah. So that's my favorite position.
>> So again, you can hear a little bit of
clap in the background. You can hear a
lot of laughter. You can hear how this
the point gets set up. And you can hear
the excitement from the audience cuz
they're like, "I've never heard anybody
state it this way before. I've never
heard it broken down so simply and so
directly and so on the nose of
understanding of what mastery looks
like." And this is why public speaking,
this is why people are afraid to speak
in public. It's not so much being in
front of an audience. It's not so much
the stress or the pressure, although
that's somewhat an issue. It's because
you are not such a [__] master yet
that you can get up there and drop an
insight that the audience has never
heard before or drop something they have
heard before but in a new way that has a
new profound impact on them that they
have not experienced before. But it's
actually not that hard if you go to
solve for it. So many people they don't
have the map and so they're playing
blind archery shooting at targets that
they can't hit and no wonder they
struggle with public speaking. These are
the targets that I'm giving you. These
are the targets that you optimize for.
Once you make your mind up, I guarantee
you can solve them. Maybe you can't
charge $50,000 a day like I do for
speaking yet, but you can move audience
who will then give you money. So, we
build them up to what's possible and we
bring them down. The contrast is there.
Before you can do this, start here. My
favorite magic trick in this business is
to find the smallest promise I can make
to my audience that will excite them to
give me money. The smallest promise
because they can believe a small promise
more easily than they can believe a big
promise. Okay? The average person has no
concept of what a million dollars is.
They they can't wrap their head around
it. They don't deal in millions of
dollars. What does the average person in
a business or financial market typically
deal with? Thousands of dollars. So
don't speak French to an Italian, right?
Speak the language that they can
understand. So we start with small. We
position. This is called paradigm.
Paradigm is the single greatest concept
on how to do a webinar. Very hard to
teach. I don't know exactly how to teach
it. So in this instance here, what I'm
doing with the audience is I am
contradicting a conventional wisdom. And
this is another thing that I do when I
write my presentations. I take
everything that people think is true and
I challenge every single one of those
supposed truths. Because here's an
algorithm for your entire life. Most
things that people accept as truth are
not actually true. So if I can show them
and break it down for them in real time,
you thought this was true, it's not. But
because it's no longer true, this is
possible. And I put so much of that into
my presentation. So this audience and
most audiences and you probably believe
that you need to make big claims if you
want to make a lot of money. Big claims
can help you make money, but there's
also a model where you can make a
smaller claim and make even more money.
And the audience is again like I have
never heard this insight or I have never
been challenged in this particular way
before. Now again, we're not just
challenge challenge challenge. You have
to wrap it around humor for it to land.
And there's also another emotional
state. This one's advanced as well
that's difficult for a lot of people to
get, but this kind of detached
amusement. I'm presenting the knowledge
to the audience as if it's true. This is
gravity. You can pretend it exists or
not, but I know it's true and I don't
really care if you believe it to be true
or not. And that detached amusement,
will you get this or not? Actually gets
the most buyin for an audience. 43 44.
Okay, here we go.
>> Is where when somebody hears it, they
say, "This changes everything." That was
good timing, right? See how that changed
when I said it, right? When you have
your mind made up, then bend reality to
your will as I just did, right?
This is such a powerful presentation
technique. Whenever you're speaking in
public, something will not go as
planned. This happens every single time
on every single speech that I've ever
done. Something in the environment will
occur that will disrupt the normal
course of business. So in this
particular case, I said this changes
everything. And when I said it,
something happened in the room. a light
went off or some light flickered or some
power source did something weird and
then I incorporated that in real time
into my presentation. Now, it's hard to
do this unless you practice it and have
the intention of it. I was speaking at a
Cole Gordon event the year before and
what happened during that event is the
AV went down. So I was on this slide. I
was making this good point and then the
AV crashed and I said this point is so
powerful that the powers to be are
trying to prevent me from giving it to
you. And then the audience was like
damn. When you can incorporate any
challenge or any disruption around you
or you can incorporate things from the
environment into the presentation in
real time. This is so impressive to the
audience that they put you on a pedestal
higher than every other presenter
because they're like, "This person is
locked in. This person is so in tune to
their environment. I want to be like
that person." So, you are showing
leadership in motion. And this is how
you get people to follow you and respond
to your messages where when somebody
hears it, they say, "This changes
everything." That was good timing,
right? See how that changed when I said
it, right? When you have your mind made
up, you will bend reality to your will
as I just did, right?
again with the laughter. Right? So,
anything that you want to set up and you
want to pay off can be done from an
amusing tone, from the excitement. A lot
of this isn't the words I'm using. It's
the cadence and it's the delivery and
it's the facial features and it's the
movement of the hands. But I am helping
the audience get that killer instinct
that most audiences don't have. And I
know these audiences so well. And this
is so much of what makes a speech so
good is knowing the audience better than
they know themselves. I know that these
people are afraid to ask for money. I
know that in a webinar specifically,
they don't know how to set it up to be
as bold and direct as they could be and
should be when it comes to asking for
money. And so I give them the frame of
how to ask for money. So there are two
levels of teaching. And I mentioned this
before, but I'll repeat it. There is
what's on the slides. This is the
conscious presentation like you do this,
you do this, you do this. It's minimally
effective in terms of transformation,
telling people what to do. If you have
kids, you know how ineffective that
typically is. showing in action what to
do in a way that is emotionally changing
somebody's physiology is much more
effective and they're less on guard for
it or they're less conscious of it. So
I'm showing them how to sell in action
even though it's not on the slide. So
I'm teaching them superficially do these
things but I'm teaching them at the deep
level as well as I demonstrate to them
sometimes the same thing I'm teaching
them consciously but sometimes in a dual
path teaching them something else in
action and in motion on a stage while
teaching them something off a slide.
What a coincidence, right? What a
coincidence. No, it was all set up. Show
not tell. Do you understand this
principle? It will change your entire
life. When you tell on a webinar, it
goes in one or not the other. When you
show it in action, they might not even
remember it, but they will remember how
they felt about it. Right? Tony Robbins
seminar. What's the number one thing
people reference with Tony Robbins
seminar? Fire, right? Oprah walks across
a hot coals and think she's unstoppable
now. She don't remember the 12 hours a
day for 7 days straight of sensory
deprivation and starvation that she went
through in order to get into a state
where she's begging to do anything to
get out of the room and then she ends on
a hot firewalk and nobody remembers
anything about Tony. They all talk about
the firewalk, right? What is your
firewalk moment?
>> They're hard.
>> It's a little hard to hear on the
recording here, but the audience goes
ooh when I mention that. And I had a
couple other ooh moments throughout. So
just like you want the spontaneous
laughter and you want the spontaneous
applause, you want the spontaneous ooh
moment as well. And so I'm giving them
an example that they know of. Tony is
the ultimate coach of all coaches. He is
the biggest name in the coaching
business. They are familiar with it. I'm
giving the example of what I'm teaching,
which is a dramatic demonstration by a
frame of reference that they can relate
to. And I'm also pantomiming it. and I'm
walking across the stage, I'm using
noise, too. Uh, when I go and like the
searing noise, the brain picks up noises
and remembers them and imprints them
more than they do with words that you
speak or even visuals. The auditorial
sense, especially of primal noises, is
really impactful. It can really help a
message land even stronger when you're
using the noises here. And again, we're
using humor as well. We're not taking
ourselves too seriously. If you can
demonstrate to your audience that at the
end of the day, none of this [__] is
really that serious. You do it.
Hopefully, it works. But as long as you
have fun, you're okay. If you can show
that, you will get so many people that
will be so connected to you and then
want to do whatever you ask them to do
after that. Um, cuz I'm trying to push
the limit of what's possible, what I can
give away for free because, you know,
I've done all the other [__] So, we'll
see. Right. But that's your benefit. Was
this good?
>> Can I show you something else for like
two more minutes? We have the time.
Okay. I didn't know if I was going to
get the bonus features on this DVD,
right? That's an hour reference, but
roll with it. Okay.
But I did. Getting permission from the
audience. Super powerful. I don't do it
as much as most people do because I
maintain such deep authority with how I
show up that it's not as necessary, but
I still like to get permission. So I
said, "Did I do a good job?" "Yes." "Do
I have your permission to share
something for two more minutes?" "Yes."
This gets buyin for the audience. This
is a real easy frame for you to
establish early on when you're public
speaking. Ask permission, get agreement,
deliver, tie it down. Was that useful?
Yes. Can I show you something else? Get
permission. Get agreement from that.
Show it. Tie it down. Was that also
helpful? Yes. Can I show you the next
thing? This cadence is super duper
powerful. The other cool thing here, and
again, this is just holding a frame. If
you have such a strong identity that you
own that stage, this is called stage
presence. You don't even need technique
after a while. I have in my head
mentally rehearsed myself owning [__]
stages forever. And I've done it in real
life for 19 years now. So when I say to
an audience, I'm like, "Here's the bonus
features of the DVD." And I go, "That's
an outdated reference. Just roll with
it." I can do things that are
antiquated, silly, and dumb. And then
the audience will just buy into it
because they're like, "Man, that dude is
bulletproof. He can stand on that stage
and command attention at will." And
again, independent of what you teach, if
you can show that, you will have
audiences that will deeply resonate with
your message, not because of what you're
saying, but because of who you are. So,
we'll see. We'll see. Let's put this up,
and see what happens. Okay, this is how
I solve problems these days. When
clients pay me a large amount of money,
which they all do, this is what I bring
to the table with them. And I wish you
to do this in your business. The
mechanism is we first remove the
unnecessary, then we optimize all this.
The last thing we do is add new
capabilities. We had the least amount of
new capabilities needed to solve the
problem. So, some of you like, man, that
webinar that Jason came on, that's a
lot. Do the minimum viable version of
that. How do you remove all the friction
to create a webinar to launch it in a
short period of time? He said, "Jason, I
don't know how to sell you yet." Don't
focus on anything. Just show up and see
if you can transform. Don't even put the
sales pitch in there yet. Right, Jason?
They always tell me Jason's the best
time to run a webinar. I said,
"Yesterday is the best time to run a
webinar, right?" They said, "Do I
automate it or do I do it live?" Yes.
So, I added this in here because the
first day when Taki introduced the fact
that I'd be speaking on day two, he told
the audience that he had paid me more
money than he'd ever paid anybody that
had spoken on his stage before it. So,
not only is it a call back to that, and
call backs as a technique for speaking
are super powerful to call back other
speakers that have come before you, to
call back to events or activities that
have occurred before you got on the
stage. But also in this particular
instance, it shows frame. I am
comfortable with charging large amounts
of money. I'm comfortable with getting
them. I'm comfortable about talking
about it. And so, the audience can then
become more comfortable as well. Also,
as an additional lever, they can be okay
with paying me large amounts of money.
And they know that if they want to hire
me, I'm expensive, but I'm worth it. So,
it's not just enough to be
premiumbriced. If you want to know a
marketing lesson here to wrap up with
this is you have to set the expectation
high and then exceed that expectation
even higher and then you can be
expensive and worth it as well.
Quadrant. Why quadrant? Four pieces of
information, right? Okay. Two major,
minor, more less. We're going all in on
social. I don't know why. I'm [__]
insane. I need to get my head exam,
right? But I want to do it. Okay. So,
here's what we discovered. And we've
been generating pretty a lot of views,
right? Uh talking head straight to
camera scripted. Pretty easy. Doesn't do
well on social very often. We still do
it cuz guys, listen. Some people see,000
views and they think that's a bad thing.
I get a little bit hard when I see,000
views, right? [laughter]
All right. That maybe got one of the
biggest pops of the day. And it's at the
end of the presentation. So, I'm
teaching them one extra thing because
they have more time. So, in this
particular case, this is a less formal
environment. It's a more mastermind
environment. A lot of successful people
there, but it's not done by the book
that you have to do a formal
presentation in this structure and this
way with all these slides. So, I didn't
know where my time was going to land.
So, I created more slides that I could
add on to the end if I had more time,
which I ended up doing. So, I'm teaching
them this lesson. And again, I'm I'm
knowing that this audience needs social.
They want social. They're trying social,
but they're struggling with social
because they don't think they get enough
views. So, I'm being the example of
somebody who's just like them. I said,
I'm also not getting a lot of views.
It's just a,000 views, but a,000 views
gets me a little hard. So, this is
pushing the line. If you want to be a
good speaker, one of the most effective
ways is to get up to the line of what's
socially acceptable to the edge of it,
but not cross it. Not only does this
make you memorable, but it also so many
people out there are so afraid of what
other people think about them that they
hate it that they censor themselves and
they wish that they could be the person
that is above the opinions of the
others, but they can't. And you're
showing them what that could look like
if they were. So, they would aspire to
be like you and look up to you. And
that's how it showed up in this part of
the presentation right here.
>> We go out to eat for a dinner. We put
two DJI on the table, one facing me, one
facing her. We write it off on our taxes
because it's a business expense, right?
We get better service than you would
ever imagine because they think that
we're food critics. [laughter]
And I just got an eight million viewed
real the other day talking about
PowerPoint for dinner. I had dinner with
8 million people. Okay? And this is
major impact with the least amount of
time. This is how you need to solve your
problems creatively. What is what will
give me the most move for the least
amount of effort. Before you do your
sign off on your presentation, end on
that highest emotional note of
aspiration and possibility and what that
could look like. So in this particular
instance, I had the quadrant there. I
had a a high note that I ended on and
this was the encore. So I had a second
high note set up to also pull out if
necessary. And I talked about dinner
with 8 million people and they saw the
matrix of it's this, it's this, it's
this. We do all of these and then we
could aspire to be this. I added that
little extra humor at the end to build a
build to build a build to crescendo and
then pay it off. And then after this I
sign off. You know, I'm Jason Flman.
It's been an honor to serve you today.
It would make me the happiest if you
take what I showed you here and put it
into action. If I did that for you and
inspired you and you do go out there and
act upon it, just kindly share the
results with me. And then audiences go
crazy. We send them off with the right
mentality to do the thing to get the
result and tell me about it. And it's
done from that emotional apex of, "Oh my
god, this was so good." If people
remember nothing else from a
presentation and they forget most of it,
they remember the last thing they felt.
So, program that last piece of
information in your presentation to end
on that emotional high note of
inspiration attached to the message of
exactly the behavior you want them to do
as a result of speaking and you will
crush it on the stage.